Chris Coenen Collection on General Tom Thumb MS254
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Cabinet cards, 1850 -- 2010; MS254.000361
  - Overview of NYC with Barnum's Museum and Brady's Gallery taken from St. Pauls Church, 1860; MS254.000470 (Box 9)
    Silverprint copy of a picture overview of NYC taken from the spire of St. Pauls; the original may have been a photo that was then turned into a print
  - Photo of Tom Thumb's Carriage at Hertzburg Circus Museum in San Antonio, Texas, 1960; MS254.000471 (Box 9)
    Silverprint of one of Tom Thumb's carriages in a museum
  - Tom Thumb in London; souvenir card; LSC, London, 1858; MS254.000472 (Box 10)
    Tom in costume
  - Tom Thumb in London; souvenir card; Life Guard; LSC, London, 1858; MS254.000473 (Box 10)
    Tom with his personal Life Guard
  - Tom Thumb in London; souvenir card; posing as Cupid; LSC, London, 1858; MS254.000474 (Box 10)
    Tom posing as statuary- Cupid
  - Tom Thumb in London; scrapboook page with calling card and inscription; LSC, London; digital only, 1858; MS254.000475 (Box 10)
    Story of a girl from Hull who was too shy to go on stage with Tom; also has one of Tom Thumb's calling cards; original in Coenen Collection
  - Charles Stratton known as General Tom Thumb; Whitney, Norwalk, Ct., 1860; MS254.000476 (Box 10)
    Series of Souvenir Cards done by Whitney, Norwalk, Ct
  - Autograph and cdv; autograph album page; Masonic?, 1863; MS254.000477 (Box 10)
    1863 cdv with signature and the name of his Lodge in Bridgeport?
  - Cynthia Stratton, Tom Thumb's mother, 1870's; MS254.000478 (Box 10)
    Portrait of Charles Stratton's mother
  - Tom Thumb carriage, 1900; MS254.000479 (Box 9)
    A carriage that may have been used by Tom or others
  - Home Natioal Bank, Middleboro (?); Board with Primo Magri; ID's on back, 1910; MS254.000480 (Box 9)
    Count Magri with gentlemen who are probably on the Board of the bank
  - Tony Pastor; show promoter; Newsboy, NY, 1910; MS254.000481 (Box 9)
    Pastor promoted some shows
  - Minnie Maddern Fiske,actress; Thumb Wedding Cake; Falk, NY, 1890; MS254.000482 (Box 9)
    In 1905, Lavinia sent the then popular actress a piece of her wedding cake from 1863 in an attempt to gain publicity and to remind the public that she was still alive; the piece of cake resides in the Smithsonian
  - Minnie Maddern Fiske, actress; 1865-1933, 1900; MS254.000483 (Box 9)
    Later picture of Minnie
  - Lilliputian Opera Company, Portsmouth, N.H.; Cook; digital only, 1875; MS254.000484 (Box 10)
    Large photo of Admiral Dot in his carriage along with other performers of the Lilliputian Opera Company in front of broadsides in Portsmouth, NH; original in Coenen Collection
  - Dageurreotyp Copy- Ct. Hist. Soc., 1850 -- 1995; MS254.000485 (Box 9)
    Copy of a dag of Tom Thumb in the Conn. Historical Society
  - Great Eastern Steamship, UK, 1860; MS254.000486 (Box 9)
    Barnum and perhaps the others travelled on the Great Eastern, largest ship of its day, across the Atlantic
  - Assawampsett, Middleboro, Mass., 1890; MS254.000487 (Box 9)
    Small steam boat that worked the Lake in Middleboro. This is not Charles Stratton's little boat.
  - Copy of a photo of Baron Magri, Count Magri and Lavinia with their carriage, 1897; MS254.000488 (Box 9)
    Probably a copy of the original which is also a stereo and used for promotional pieces
  - Lavinia in her buggy in Middleboro, 1915; MS254.000489 (Box 9)
    Lavinia in her little push carriage, probably at home
  - Lavinia on her porch, Middleboro, 1915; MS254.000490 (Box 9)
    Lavinia standing on her porch, probably Middleboro
  - Count Magri and Lavinia in front of the little store in Middleboro, Primo's Pastime, 1915; MS254.000491 (Box 9)
    Perhaps a later print of Primo and Lavinia in front of the store
  - Count Magri and Lavinia in front of the little store in Middleboro, Primo's Pastime II, 1915; MS254.000492 (Box 9)
  - Tom Thumb Carriage at UNH, Durham, NH; note on back, 1925; MS254.000493 (Box 9)
    The carriage is now in the Ford Museum
  - Colorized copy of an 1858 photo by LSC, 1858 -- 2010; MS254.000494 (Box 9)
    Copy
  - Barnum Statue at Seaside Park, Bridgeport, 1885; MS254.000495 (Box 10)
    A statue of Barnum was erected in Seaside Pard
  - Brooklyn Yacht Club Regatta, 1880; MS254.000496 (Box 10)
    Charles Stratton had a yacht, The Maggie B,,that he raced with the Brooklyn Yacht Club; probably not this race
  - Copy of a daguerrotype of Tom Thumb, 1850 -- 2010; MS254.000497 (Box 10)
    Dag copy of Tom about age twelve
  - Copy of photo of Tom Thumb as Napoleon; National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian (NPG), 1860 -- 1996; MS254.000498 (Box 10)
    Tom as Napoleon; LSC
  - Lavinia Warren; Brady, NPG, 1863; MS254.000499 (Box 10)
    Lavinia probably before the wedding; these are from the original negative
  - Commodore Nutt and Minnie Warren, Brady; NPG, 1865; MS254.000500 (Box 10)
    Nutt and Minnie; probably after their trip to Europe
  - Minnie Warren and Mrs Bleeker; NPG; Brady, 1865; MS254.000501 (Box 10)
    Mrs. Bleeker was the wife of Sylvester Bleeker; she died in 1883, in the Milwaukee Hotel fire; Minnie died in 1878
  - Lavinia and borrowed baby, Brady; NPG, 1864; MS254.000502 (Box 10)
    One of three baby portraits; there was probably a fourth negative that got damaged
  - Lavinia and borrowed baby, Brady; NPG II, 1864; MS254.000503 (Box 10)
    Anotheer baby variation
  - Borrowed baby and nurse; NPG, 1864; MS254.000504 (Box 10)
    The nurse who tended to the baby
  - Charles Stratton and E. Anthony; NPG, 1865; MS254.000505 (Box 10)
    Anthony published many of the photographs that Tom Thumb sold at his shows
  - Commodore Nutt as drummer; Brady; NPG, 1865; MS254.000506 (Box 10)
    Nutt dressed in a role
  - Edward Newwell; Brady; NPG, 1864; MS254.000507 (Box 10)
    Newell eventually married Minnie Warren
  - Charles Stratton and Lavinia Warren; Brady; NPG, 1865; MS254.000508 (Box 10)
  - Charles and Lavinia; Brady; NPG, 1865; MS254.000509 (Box 10)
  - Tom Thumb Carriage display, 1950; MS254.000510 (Box 10)
    Display of a "Tom Thumb Carriage"; probably England
  - Tom Thumb Carriage at Herzberg Circus Collection, 1960; MS254.000511 (Box 10)
    Display of the coach in San Antonio
  - Tom Thumb Carriage at Hertzberg with Diane Darby on top; info on back, 1960; MS254.000512 (Box 10)
    Coach
  - Copy of poster announcing Barnum's 1881 Circus with Tom and Lavinia, 1881 -- 1996; MS254.000513 (Box 10)
    Charles Stratton and Lavinia Warren travelled with Barnum's 1881 circus
  - Newsphoto taken around Lavinia's seventy-fifth birthday; Count's bicycle; info on back, 1916; MS254.000514 (Box 10)
    1916 newsphoto
  - Newsphoto of Primo and Lavinia playing music, 1916; MS254.000515 (Box 10)
  - Lavinia and Primo; South Middleboro Grange, 1914; MS254.000516 (Box 4)
    This photo hung in the South Middleboro Grange
  - Primo and Ernesto Magri at Auburn Prison, NY, 1915; MS254.000517 (Box 4)
    Prisons often toured visitors; with Warden George Benham and Deputy Warden, Allen Tupper
  - Overview of NYC with Barnum's Museum and Brady's Gallery taken from St. Pauls Church, 1860; MS254.000518 (Box 4)
- Cartes-de-visite, 1858 -- 1940; MS254.000519
  This series contains cartes-de-visite related to Tom Thumb, including images of Charles Stratton, Lavinia Warren, Commodore Nutt, Minnie Warren, Count Primo Magri, Ernesto Magri, P. T. Barnum, Jennie Quigley, Sarah and Lucy Adams, and Zoe Meleke. The carte-de-visite is a type of small photograph that was often traded among friends in the late 19th century.
  - Charles S. Stratton and M. Lavinia Warren in front of a decorative backdrop with palm trees, 1860 -- 1869; MS254.000520 (Box 20)
    Charles S. Stratton (General Tom Thumb) and his wife, M. Lavinia Warren, probably taken on their tour of Italy.
  - George Washington Morrison Nutt and Minnie Warren in theatrical costumes, 1863; MS254.000521 (Box 20)
    George Washington Morrison Nutt (Commodore Nutt) and Minnie Warren dressed in theatrical costumes. Autographed by Nutt.
  - M. Lavinia Warren next to a horse, 1920 -- 1929; MS254.000522 (Box 20)
    M. Lavinia Warren standing next to a horse outside of a house. This photograph is a later 1920s reprint of an image originally taken in 1879.
  - Tom Thumb in yachting costume, 1863 February 14; MS254.000523 (Box 20)
    Photographed by J.A. Williams, No 2. Downing's Block, Newport, RI.
  - Tom Thumb dressed as Napoleon, 1860; MS254.000524 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton dressed in his Napoleon costume at about age ten; copy of a daguerreotype c. 1848
  - Charles Stratton in a suit, 1865; MS254.000525 (Box 20)
    Copy of an earlier photograph; perhaps a daguerreotype; blank back
  - General Tom Thumb 1860, MS254.000526 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton in a suit taken by the London Stereoscopic Company
  - General Tom Thumb 1860, MS254.000527 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton dressed as Napoleon taken by the London Stereoscopic Company
  - General Tom Thumb 1860, MS254.000528 (Box 20)
    Back Showing LSC logo
  - General Tom Thumb 1860, MS254.000529 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton dressed as Highlander taken by the London Stereoscopic Company
  - General Tom Thumb 1860, MS254.000530 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton dressed as a Tar (British Sailor) by the London Stereoscopic Company
  - Charles Stratton posed with little furniture, 1860; MS254.000531 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton posed with some of his miniature furniture; the little chair was a lifelong prop; signed "Gen Tom Thumb" by Stratton on back
  - Signed cdv, 1860; MS254.000532 (Box 20)
    Gen Tom Thumb signature
  - General Tom Thumb as Napoleon, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000533 (Box 20)
    Stratton dressed as Napoleon by E. T. Whitney of Norwalk, CT
  - Charles Stratton in suit, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000534 (Box 20)
    Stratton dressed in a suit by E. T. Whitney of Norwalk, CT; handcolored
  - Charles Stratton in suit, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000535 (Box 20)
    Strton dressed in suit by Whitney of Norwalk, CT
  - Stratton as Highlander, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000536 (Box 20)
    Stratton dressed as a Scottish Highlander by Whitney of Norwalk, CT
  - Stratton as Sailor, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000537 (Box 20)
    Stratton as a sailor by Whitney of Norwalk, CT
  - Tom Thumb posing as statue, 1860 -- 1862; MS254.000538 (Box 20)
    Tom Thumb posing as statuary by J. Stevenson, 140 Grand St., Brooklyn, E. D.
  - Lavinia Warren in a wedding dress, 1863; MS254.000539 (Box 20)
    Early view of Lavinia in a wedding dress; possibly a copy photo
  - Lavinia Warren with Horatio Perkins, 1863; MS254.000540 (Box 20)
    Lavinia with Horatio Perkins; ID; possible copy photo
  - Lavinia Warren in check dress, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000541 (Box 20)
    Lavinia by Brady; early 1963
  - Lavinia Warren by studio post; signed, 1863; MS254.000542 (Box 20)
    Studio shot of Lavinia by Charles Fredricks, NY; signed on back
  - Lavinia Warren in Boston, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000543 (Box 20)
    Early Lavinia probably in Boston by Tomlinson
  - Charles Stratton with W. B. Harrison, 1863; MS254.000544 (Box 20)
    Tom Thumb with friend and Barnum employee, W. B. Harrison by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren by Gurney, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000545 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren, probably just before her marriage to Charles Stratton; by J. Gurney, NY
  - Lavinia Warren, Boston, 1862; MS254.000546 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in Boston, probably Dec. 1862; by Tomlinson, Boston
  - Lavinia Warren, handcolored, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000547 (Box 20)
    Handcolored view of Lavinia Warren by Appleton & Co., NY
  - Lavinia Warren, not colored variation of #22, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000548 (Box 20)
    Original version of colored cdv #22
  - Lavinia Warren, white dress, 1862; MS254.000549 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in white dress by Silsbee, Case & Co., later Case & Getchell, Boston; "From Dec. 3, 1862"
  - Lavinia Warren in white dress, Fredricks, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000550 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in a white dress by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren, white dress and cape, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000551 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in a white dress with a cape, by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren in white dress and cape, handcolored, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000552 (Box 20)
    Hand colored version of #26; Tax Stamp (1864-66) on back canceled "J. B. Jay, Aug. 2, 1866"
  - Lavinia Warren with flower vase, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000553 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren posed with flower vase by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren with flower vase and chair, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000554 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren posed with flowers and chair, by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren next to chair, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000555 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren posed leaning on chair by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren next to chair, handcolored, #30, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000556 (Box 20)
    Hand colored version of #30 by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren leaning on chair, handcolored, #30, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000557 (Box 20)
    Handcolored version of #30, by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren in white dress by chair, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000558 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren by chair, probably a copy
  - Lavinia in black dress, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000559 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in a black dress showing her ankle
  - Lavinia Warren in black dress, ankle, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000560 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in black dress by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren in black dress by Gurney, NY, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000561 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in black dress, showing ankle by J. Gurney, NY; Fredricks was probably the original photographer for these views
  - Lavinia Warren, black dress, ankle;Brady backmark, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000562 (Box 20)
    Lavinia showing ankle with Brady logo, but probably done by Fredricks
  - Lavinia with ermine cape, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000563 (Box 20)
    Lavinia with an ermine cape, given as a gift
  - Lavinia Warren and Charles Stratton, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000564 (Box 20)
    Lavinia and Charles around the time of their wedding by Fredricks, NY
  - Lavinia Warren and Charles Stratton; hand, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000565 (Box 20)
    Lavinia and Charles near the time of their weddding
  - Lavinia Warren in dark dress, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000566 (Box 20)
    Lavinia by Fredricks, NY
  - Charles Sratton with tophat, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000567 (Box 20)
    Charles posed next to a chair with his cap and someone's top hat
  - Lavinia Warren; seated; ermine cape, 1862 -- 1863; MS254.000568 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren; seated with her ermine cape;by Appleton, NY
  - Charles Stratton; traveling clothes, 1863; MS254.000569 (Box 20)
    Charles Stratton in traveling clothes by Partridge of Bridgeport, CT
  - Lavinia Warren; handkerchief, 1863; MS254.000570 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in dark dress holding handkerchief by Partridge of Bridgeport, CT
  - Composite CDV of Lavinia and Charles, 1863; MS254.000571 (Box 20)
    Composite montage of photos taken around the time of the wedding
  - Wedding costumes-I, 1863; MS254.000572 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony portrait probably done on Feb. 9, 1863 at Brady's studio; printed signatures on back; printed signatures appear on the backs of most of the original wedding cdv's
  - Wedding costumes- II, 1863; MS254.000573 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony portrai taken just before the wedding
  - Wedding costumes- III, 1863; MS254.000574 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony portrait just before wedding
  - Wedding costumes- IV, 1863; MS254.000575 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony portrait taken just before wedding
  - Charles Stratton; The Lilliputian Bridegroom- I, 1863; MS254.000576 (Box 20)
    Charles taken just before the wedding by Brady/Anthony; printed signature
  - Charles Stratton; The Lilliputian Bridegroom- II, 1863; MS254.000577 (Box 20)
    Charles before the wedding
  - Lavinia Warren; The Fairy Bride, 1863; MS254.000578 (Box 20)
    Lavinia Warren in her Wedding dress by Brady Anthony
  - Lavinia and Charles in their wedding costumes; variant- I, 1863; MS254.000579 (Box 20)
    Another studio shot ust before the wedding; Brady/Anthony; printed signatures
  - Lavinia and Charles in their wedding costumes; variant- II, 1863; MS254.000580 (Box 20)
    Another studio shot just before the wedding; Brady/Anthony; printed signatures
  - Lavinia and Charles in their wedding costumes; variant 2-I, 1863; MS254.000581 (Box 20)
    Studio shot of Tom and Lavinia by Brady/Anthony
  - Lavinia and Charles in their wedding costumes; variant 2-II; with 2 cents tax stamp, 1863 -- 1864; MS254.000582 (Box 20)
    Studio shot by Brady/Anthony; note change of date under photo; Civil War tax stamp on back; probably printed in 1864
  - Lavinia and Charles in their wedding costumes; variant 2-III, 1863; MS254.000583 (Box 20)
    Studio shot by Brady/Anthony
  - Copy photo of Charles Stratton and Lavinia Warren in their wedding costumes, 1863 -- 1864; MS254.000584 (Box 20)
    Photographers often copied photos for sale; sold by John Pittock of Pittsburgh, PA
  - Mr. and Mrs." General Tom Thumb" in their Wedding Costumes, 1863; MS254.000585 (Box 20)
    Taken just before the wedding; Brady, NY; facsimiie signatures
  - Mr. and Mrs. Tom Thumb; tax stamp, 1864; MS254.000586 (Box 20)
    Taken after the wedding; the Civil War tax stamp was introduced in 1864
  - Engraved CDV of P.T. Barnum with the wedding party; reception dress story on back, 1863 -- 1864; MS254.000587 (Box 20)
    Engraved image of Barnum added to a wedding group photo; story of the reception dress by Mme. Demorest on back
  - The Reception Dress by Brady, 1863; MS254.000588 (Box 20)
    Lavinia models the reception dress; story on back
  - Tom Thumb and Lavinia; Reception Dress by Brady, 1863; MS254.000589 (Box 20)
    Taken just before the wedding; story of the dress on back
  - Tom and Lavinia; Reception Dress variation, 1863; MS254.000590 (Box 20)
    A variation of the Reception Dress; story on back
  - Tom and Lavinia with a bearded man; Reception Dress, 1863; MS254.000591 (Box 20)
    Tom and Lavinia with an unidentified bearde man; Reception Dress story
  - Charles Stratton dressed as Napoleon; Boston, 1863; MS254.000592 (Box 20)
    Tom Thumb in his Napolean outfit by Silsbee, Case & Co., Boston
  - Mr. & Mrs. General Tom Thumb; Napolean, 1863; MS254.000593 (Box 20)
    Taken before the wedding by Brady/Anthony
  - Mr. & Mrs. Tom Thumb; Napolean II, 1863; MS254.000594 (Box 20)
    Taken before the wedding by Brady/ Anthony
  - The Marriage of Gen'l Tom Thumb, 1863; MS254.000595 (Box 20)
    Staged wedding scene by Brady/Anthony with Commodore Nutt and Minnie Warren
  - The Marriage II, 1863; MS254.000596 (Box 20)
  - The Marriage III, 1863; MS254.000597 (Box 20)
  - The Marriage IV, 1863; MS254.000598 (Box 20)
  - The Marriage V, 1863; MS254.000599 (Box 20)
  - Bishop Potter, New York; Brady, 1863; MS254.000600 (Box 20)
    Bishop Potter was originally going to perform the wedding ceremony but relented when parishioners objected
  - The Fairy Wedding Group; Brady, 1863; MS254.000601 (Box 20)
    The iconic wedding pose probably taken the day before the wedding by Brady.
  - The Fairy Wedding Group copy; California, 1863; MS254.000602 (Box 20)
    A copy print of the wedding group with ID on back; Angels Camp, Calaveras County, Calif.
  - Reverse of print 77, 1863; MS254.000603 (Box 20)
    Reverse of 77 with ID
  - Fairy Wedding group II, 1863; MS254.000604 (Box 20)
    Taken just prior to the wedding by Brady
  - Fairy Wedding group III, 1863; MS254.000605 (Box 20)
  - Fairy Wedding group; mount variation, 1863; MS254.000606 (Box 20)
    Taken prior to the wedding
  - Copy of Engraving of Tom and Lavinia, 1863; MS254.000607 (Box 20)
    Copy of an engraving, possibly from Harpers
  - Minnie Warren (Huldah Pierce Bump), 1863; MS254.000608 (Box 20)
    Copy of a wedding photo of Minnie
  - Miss Minnie Warren, The Bidesmaid, 1863; MS254.000609 (Box 20)
    Minnie dressed for wedding by Brady shortly before the wedding
  - Misses Lavinia & Minnie Warren, 1863; MS254.000610 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren, Groomsman & Bridesmaid, 1863; MS254.000611 (Box 20)
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren, Groomsman & Bridesmaid II, 1863; MS254.000612 (Box 20)
    Brady/ Anthony
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren, III, 1863; MS254.000613 (Box 20)
  - Comm. Nutt & Minnie Warren, Watch, 1863; MS254.000614 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony; Nutt looks at watch
  - Nutt and Minnie; The Propposal, 1863; MS254.000615 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony; Nutt on one knee with pretend proposal
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren, dress variation, 1863; MS254.000616 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony, Minnie has a different dress
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren; dress variation II, 1863; MS254.000617 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony, Minnie has a different dress II
  - Commodore Nutt & Minnie Warren; Nutt in uniform, 1863; MS254.000618 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony, Nutt in Commodore outfit
  - Tom Thumb, Lavinia Warren, Commodore Nutt and WB Harrison, 1863; MS254.000619 (Box 20)
    Brady/Anthony; WB Harrison was a comic actor who worked for Barnum and introduced Lavinia in her debut
  - CDV print of Tom and Lavinia, wedding costumes, 1863; MS254.000620 (Box 20)
    Print for commercial sale
  - Tom and Lavinia in wedding costumes, 1863; MS254.000621 (Box 20)
    Nice pose of Tom and Lavinia
  - Tom Thumb with vase; Fredricks, NY, 1863; MS254.000622 (Box 20)
    Taken before the wedding
  - Tom and Lavinia with vase; Fredricks, NY, 1863; MS254.000623 (Box 20)
  - Tom and Lavinia with vase II; Fredricks, NY, 1863; MS254.000624 (Box 20)
  - Tom and Lavinia in their traveling clothes; Anthony,NY, 1862; MS254.000625 (Box 20)
    Taken a week or two before the wedding; Barnum had promised to send Lavinia to Europe
  - Lavinia Warren in her traveling outfit; FFredricks, NY, 1863; MS254.000626 (Box 20)
    Taken several weeks before the wedding
  - Lavinia in a traveling outfit; Appleton, NY, 1863; MS254.000627 (Box 20)
  - Lavinia in a traveling outfit or winter dress with muff by Appleton, 1863; MS254.000628 (Box 20)
    Taken before the wedding; apparently given to a friend near Middleborough by Lavinia
  - The Lilliputian Card Party; hand colored; Brady/Anthony, 1863; MS254.000629 (Box 20)
    Probably taken during the photo shoot just before the wedding
  - The Lilliputian Card Party; Brady/Anthony, 1863; MS254.000630 (Box 20)
    Staged Card Party
  - The Lillputian Card Party; Brady/Anthony; variation, 1863; MS254.000631 (Box 20)
    Staged card party variant
  - Nutt and Minnie Playing Chess; Brady/Anthony, 1863; MS254.000632 (Box 20)
    Staged chess match; part of the series taken by Brady ust before the wedding
  - Nutt and Minnie Playing Chess; Brady/Anthony; variation, 1863; MS254.000633 (Box 20)
    Another chess match
  - Nutt and Minnie Playing Chess; Brady/Anthony; variation II, 1863; MS254.000634 (Box 20)
  - Copy photo of Charles and Lavinia around the wedding, 1863 -- 1865; MS254.000635 (Box 20)
    Tom and Lavinia or Barnum brought cdv's when they went to England; some of these were copied by English photographers to satisfy the demand before English photos were available; copied by Bentley of Stockport, UK
  - Commodore Nutt (George Washington Morrison Nutt) and Minnie Warren by Bentley, Stockport, 1865; MS254.000636 (Box 20)
    Taken in UK during their first visit
  - Engraving of wedding photo with P.T. Barnum added, 1863; MS254.000637 (Box 20)
    Barnum added to the wedding group
  - George Washington Nutt/Commodore Nutt, 1862; MS254.000638 (Box 20)
    Barnum hired Nutt as a replacement for Tom Thumb
  - Commodore Nutt, 1862; MS254.000639 (Box 20)
    CDV Variation
  - P.T. Barnum and Commodore Nutt, 1862; MS254.000640 (Box 20)
    PT Barnum and Commodore Nutt around the time he was hired by Barnum
  - P.T.Barnum and Commodore Nutt II, 1862; MS254.000641 (Box 20)